empireofthekop.com 2019-03-30

# Privacy Policy - The Empire of The Kop

_Version 1.0_ _Effective 25 th May 2018_

This Privacy Policy describes how and when Rocket Sports Internet Limited ("Rocket") collects, uses, and shares your information when you use any of Rocket's web properties (the "Services"), which include, but are not limited to, caughtoffside.com, chelsea-news.co, empireofthekop.com, fanatix.com, manunitedzone.com, strettynews.com, talkchelsea.net, app.football-italia.net and app.football-espana.net. 

## Personally Identifiable Information

Rocket does not collect any direct personally identifiable information ("PII") such as your name, address, email address, phone number, age, gender, or social media account details. 

## Anonymous Identifiers

Rocket collects statistical information about visitors to the Services, including which pages are visited and when they are visited. Information recorded may include your IP address, browser type, operating system, the referring web page, pages visited, location, your mobile carrier, device and application IDs, and search terms. This information is aggregated for statistical purposes, and is never connected to any PII and remains anonymous. This analysis is provided and managed by Google Analytics. Any statistical information collected via Google Analytics for these purposes is not shared outside of this system. 

## Legitimate Interest

Under the data protection laws entering in to force in Europe in 2018 there are a number of justifications that websites can use for lawfully collecting and processing information about their visitors. One such justification is named "Legitimate Interest" and, broadly, means that websites can process visitor information if they have a genuine and legitimate reason, and are not harming any individuals' rights and interests. 

Our goal at Rocket is to provide a high quality free sports news service. To help keep this service free we provide our advertising partners with anonymised data about visitors to our websites, such that these partners may target their promotional messages more appropriately to the most relevant audiences. Without this anonymised data these partners would pay significantly less to promote their goods and services, and our service would not be sustainable. 

We believe that providing this anonymised data, in a way which does not harm any of your rights or interests, is in our legitimate interest in continuing to provide our free news service. 

## Social & Sharing Platforms

Rocket uses code provided by various social media & sharing platforms to provide a number of features and enhancements, as outlined below. At no time does Rocket store, process or receive any information from these services about you or your account(s) with them. These third-party service providers may use cookies and other technologies to collect information about your use of our Services and other websites and services, including your IP address, device ID, and pages viewed. 

  * Twitter, Instagram and YouTube enhance our articles by allowing us to display content from their users directly
  * Facebook provides our comments feature and allows discussion on individual articles
  * Shareaholic provides a simple means for you to share our articles on many popular social platforms

## Advertising

Rocket displays advertising from a variety of partners in order to fund its activities. These partners may use cookies or other means to target their adverts based on a variety of criteria, such as the country you are in (determined by your device's settings or IP address), the type of device you are using, and which other websites or online properties you have visited in the past. At no point does Rocket provide any advertisers with any PII, nor do we receive any data from them. 

Some of our advertising partners allow you to opt out of their anonymous tracking systems, meaning you will see more generic and less tailored advertising from them. If you wish to opt out from any of these, please follow these links: 

## Cookies

Like many websites, we use "cookie" technology to collect additional website usage data and to improve our Services, but we do not explicitly require cookies for many parts of our Services. A cookie is a small data file that is transferred to your computer's hard disk. Rocket may use both session cookies and persistent cookies to better understand how you interact with our Services, to monitor aggregate usage by our users and web traffic routing on our Services, and to customize and improve our Services. Most Internet browsers automatically accept cookies. If you do not want cookies from Rocket or other websites, you can instruct your browser, by changing its settings, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. However, some Services may not function properly if you disable cookies. 

## Log Data

Our servers automatically record information ("Log Data") created by your use of the Services. Log Data may include information such as your IP address, browser type, operating system, the referring web page, pages visited, location, your mobile carrier, device and application IDs, and search terms. We receive Log Data when you interact with our Services, such as when you visit our website(s). Rocket uses Log Data to provide our Services and to measure, customize, and improve them. If not already done earlier, we will either delete Log Data or remove any common identifiers, such as your full IP address, after 18 months. 

## Law and Harm

Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in this Policy, we may preserve or disclose your information if we believe that it is reasonably necessary to comply with a law, regulation or legal request; to protect the safety of any person; to address fraud, security or technical issues; or to protect Rocket's rights or property. However, nothing in this Privacy Policy is intended to limit any legal defences or objections that you may have to a third party's, including a government's, request to disclose your information. 

## Business Transfers

In the event that Rocket is involved in a bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets, your information may be sold or transferred as part of that transaction. The promises in this Privacy Policy will apply to your information as transferred to the new entity. 

## Our Policy Towards Children

Our Services are not directed to persons under 13. If you become aware that your child has provided us with personal information without your consent, please email [help@fanatix.com](mailto:help@fanatix.com). We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information, we take steps to remove such information and terminate the child's account. 

## Changes to this Policy

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time, and will endeavour to draw your attention to any material changes via more prominent messaging on the Services. The most current version of the policy will govern our use of your information.
